cast.org 2014-11-23

# CAST: Privacy Policy

CAST is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit [www.cast.org](http://www.cast.org/) and all other CAST sites. 

These sites servers automatically collect nonpersonal data such as IP addresses, domain names of sites that referred you (such as search engines), and information about the pages you access. This information is used only for CAST's internal statistical analysis, never for marketing.

Cookies are used by the sites servers to maintain user's preferences. Cookies are not tied to personally identifiable information. If you do not wish to use cookies, please configure your browser to prevent their use.

In general, information collected for the purpose of facilitating your use of these sites will not be shared with any third party without your consent. We may ask you for such information on our feedback forms, online surveys, or if you contact us regarding these sites. Disclosure of such information is always optional and information is never disclosed to a third party without your consent.

Our servers will not automatically record your name or e-mail address. Your e-mail address and other personal identifying data will not be known to CAST unless you voluntarily submit them to us. If you request email information or updates from CAST, and later decide you don’t want to receive these, you can always opt out. Email your request to [webeditor@cast.org](mailto:webeditor@cast.org).

Those who register as members of the National UDL Consortium receive at least one email newsletter after they register. To opt out, reply to the email with "unsubscribe" in the subject line.

#### Products, Services, Forums, Message Boards, etc.

Some online tools available through the CAST site require users to register using a partial name and email address. CAST does not collect information that can be used to identify individuals. CAST uses email addresses for password reminders/retrieval only. Some applications gives users the option to subscribe to CAST newsletters when they register; those newsletters will be sent only to email addresses provided by the users themselves. When registering for professional development services, you may be required to provide data such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and credit card/financial information. This information is needed to verify your identity and to complete financial transactions. We may use your telephone number or email address to contact you if we have trouble processing your order. We will never use your telephone number for sales or marketing purposes.

Any user who posts information on message boards or other such venues on these sites does so for public communication and understands that such information will be publicly available. Users who post information in this manner cannot expect privacy or confidentiality regarding such information.

#### External sites

These sites contain links to other sites. CAST is not responsible for the privacy practices, content, or services of those sites. Links are provided as potential resources only and do not constitute any endorsement by CAST. They should be evaluated carefully. If you find any linked content you consider inappropriate, please bring the matter to our attention by sending an email to [webeditor@cast.org](mailto:webeditor@cast.org)

#### Security

These sites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under our control. Regular back-ups are performed on these sites servers and all database information is stored in secured directories.

#### Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, we may need to disclose personal information about you when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or to comply with legal processes.

#### Your Agreement

By using these sites, you acknowledge and agree to this privacy policy. If you do not agree to this privacy policy, please do not use these sites. We reserve the right to change, add, or remove all or part of our privacy policy at any time by posting the changes on this page. Your continued use of the CAST sites following the posting of changes to these terms means you accept such changes.
